Eufrat Tsaqib Qasthari

eutsat@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/eufat/ | (+62) 87881343875

Summary

Engineer with over 5 years of experience applying Al, IoT, and cloud technologies to production systems. Experience in delivering cloud technology systems with cutting-edge tech that are used by millions of users and also have built an early-stage startup.

Experiences

Engineering Specialist (AI/ML), LinkAja (January 2022-Present)

Assistant Manager.

Senior Engineer (Al/ML), LinkAja (May 2020-December 2021)

Go-to person for all Al/ML production systems at the leading digital financial service from the largest SOEs (BUMN) in Indonesia (BNI, BRI, BTN, Mandiri, Telkomsel, Pertamina etc.)

Build Al/ML infrastructure, platform, and services for eKYC, chatbot, customer segmentation, fraud detection and credit scoring for 80+ million users and 8+ million inference monthly. Using Python, JavaScript, Kubernetes, GPUs, Kubeflow, Keras, TensorFlow, PyTorch, etc.

Software Engineer, Nodeflux (December 2018-May 2020)

Hired before graduation in the largest computer vision Al company in Indonesia (NVIDIA Partner and ranked 25th worldwide in NIST FRVT). Developed a core cloud platform for deep learning analytics with the entire documentation site. Developed eKYC API for identifying 150+ million Indonesian identities and COVID-19 public mobility monitoring system on top of 2600+ CCTVs across Jakarta and Bandung. Using Go, Python, Kubernetes, GPUs, gRPC etc.

Software Engineer Intern, Nodeflux (July 2018-August 2018)

Benchmark object-detection systems with JavaScript, Python, MQ systems, ELK and Websocket. Benchmark video streaming protocols and decoders with RTSP, DASH and WebRTC.

Co-founder, Replus (June 2019-May 2020)

Technical Lead & Co-founder, Replus (June 2017-May 2019)

Made a small company (PT) while still in college, supported with 690M IDR (equivalent to 50K USD) from multiple competitions and sponsors. Led software engineering team to deliver PWA application with near real-time IoT integration. Using JavaScript, Polymer, MQTT, Google Cloud, etc.

Education

University of Indonesia, Bachelor of Science (August 2015-August 2019)

Physics Major, System and Instrumentation Minor. Nominated for most outstanding student.

Research on Hyperspectral Computer Vision at Bio-Imaging Physics Research Group. Initiating DNN usage for hyperspectral imagery with Specim FX-10 hyperspectral camera.

Chief Programmer KRAI (ABU ROBOCON) Division at University Robotics Team.

Skills

Programming Languages: Python, JavaScript, Go and C

Tools: Vim, Git, K8s, TensorFlow, PyTorch, GPUs, MQ, Polymer, React, Redux, Google Cloud and AWS

Awards

PPBT Startup Funding, Selected National (2018)

NYALA Smart Energy Hackathon, 2nd National (2018)

App Innovation Challenge Compfest 9, Finalist National (2018)

Selected PKM-GT RISTEKDIKTI, National (2017)

KRAI (ABU ROBOCON) Robotics Competition, 2nd Regional 2 Level (2016)

Certificates

EF SET English Certificate, C2 Proficient (2022)

Triplebyte Backend Engineering Certificate, Level 3 Proficient (2022)

Talks

Intro to Git for Research and Software Project, Department of Physics University of Indonesia (2018)

GPU on Kubernetes for Machine Learning, Jakarta Kubernetes Meetup (2019)

Intro to Storage in Kubernetes, Jakarta Kubernetes Meetup (2021)

Startup Mechanics, LinkAja Sharing Session (2021)

AutoML (Includes HPO and NAS), LinkAja Sharing Session (2022)